tapjoy.com 2015-06-17

# Tapjoy Privacy Policy | Tapjoy Info

Tapjoy, Inc., our subsidiaries and affiliated companies (collectively, “Tapjoy,” “we,” “us,” “our”) cares about our users’ privacy and is committed to disclosing our data practices. This Privacy Policy explains how Tapjoy collects, uses, and shares information from and about you when you (i) use mobile applications from app publishers (“Publisher(s)”) that integrate Tapjoy ads and/or otherwise engage with the Tapjoy services (“Tapjoy Ad Platform”); and/or (ii) visit the Tapjoy websites including www.my.tapjoy.com or [www.tapjoy.com ](http://home.tapjoy.com/) (“Tapjoy Web Services”) (the Tapjoy Ad Platform and the Tapjoy Web Services are referred to hereinafter as the “Tapjoy Services”). Tapjoy is a Delaware corporation with headquarters located in San Francisco, California, U.S. This Privacy Policy is governed under the laws of the State of California, U.S.

Tapjoy is a member of the Interactive Advertising Bureau (“IAB”) and abides by the IAB Code of Conduct including its “Self Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.” More information about the IAB may be found [here](http://www.iab.net/public_policy/codeofconduct). If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@tapjoy.com](mailto:privacy@tapjoy.com). 

This Privacy Policy contains the following sections:

  * Tapjoy Ad Platform Privacy Practices
  * Tapjoy Web Services Privacy Practices
  * Tapjoy Privacy Practices for Both the Ad Platform and Web Services

## Tapjoy Ad Platform Privacy Practices

## 1\. The Information We Collect

When you interact with a mobile application that has partnered with Tapjoy for the purpose of displaying advertisements within the app (“Partner App(s)”), we and/or our service providers may collect a variety of information about your device and the Tapjoy-originated ads that you view. Each of our Partner Apps is responsible for obtaining all applicable consents to enable us to collect information from your device. This information does not disclose to us your personal identity, but it allows us to recognize your mobile device so that we can measure when your device uses our partner apps. The information we collect may include the following:

  * Information about your device. We may collect some or all of the following information about your device: device identifier, which may include Android ID, ID for Advertising (IDFA), ID for Vendors (IDFV), MAC address, International Mobile Equipment Identity (IMEI), or other unique device identifiers; device type (e.g., mobile, tablet); operating system (e.g., Android, iOS); network provider; IP address; mobile browser (e.g., Safari, Chrome, etc.); the carrier user ID (a number uniquely allocated to you by your network provider); Tapjoy SDK version; timestamp; API key (identifier for application); application version; manufacturer and device model; language setting; time zone; network status type (such as WiFi); list of installed apps (the applications and/or processes which are installed or run on your device while the Partner App is active or inactive).
  * Precise Location Information and How to Opt Out of Location Tracking. We may collect and process information about your mobile device’s GPS location (including the latitude, longitude or altitude of your mobile device) and the time the location information was recorded to customize the Tapjoy-originated ads you view. You can stop the collection of this data at any time by disabling the GPS or other location-tracking functions on your device, provided your device allows you to do this. See your device manufacturer’s instructions for further details.
  * Information about ads you view. We collect some or all of the following information about the ads you view: (i) what the ad is about; (ii) the ad type (e.g. whether the ad is a text, image, or video); (iii) where the ad is displayed; and (iv) certain information regarding what you do when interacting with or after viewing the ad (e.g. whether you proceed to purchase a product advertised). If an advertiser (“Advertiser”) uses one of our advertising solutions that involves the collection of voluntary information from you as part of an ad, e.g. serving an ad that contains an advertiser questionnaire, and if we collect such information that you voluntarily provide in response to such ads, then we shall forward such information directly to the Advertiser, and such information will be governed by the Advertiser’s privacy policy.
  * Information from our partners. Our Partner Apps and other third party partners may sometimes disclose to us information they have separately collected about you so that we can improve the relevance of the ads we serve on their behalf. They do this in accordance with their own privacy policies and subject to their own applicable legal requirements. 
  * Customer Support. If while using one of our Partner Apps you recognize a problem with an integrated Tapjoy ad and notify us of the problem or otherwise contact us via email or with a question, we will ask for your email address or other contact information so that you can receive a response.

### 2\. How we Use the Information we Collect

We use the information we collect through the Tapjoy Ad Platform in order to:

  * Display interest-based advertising customized to individuals’ inferred interests, preferences and locations, and to analyze the effectiveness of the ads. The information we collect also helps us to provide filtering options for Publishers to manage ads appearing in their Partner Apps, and to provide targeting options for Advertisers. For example, the information we collect helps us to avoid presenting you with ads that you have already seen, and helps our Advertiser clients to serve ads that are more likely to be of interest to you.
  * Track your engagement with ads and to ensure you receive any virtual awards you have earned via ad engagements.
  * Respond to your customer support inquiries and to facilitate accurate resolution of any customer support problems that may arise.
  * Perform analysis and research aimed at improving our services.
  * Display contextual advertising, frequency capping of displayed ads, conversion tracking, reporting and security and fraud detection. 
  * Tapjoy shall retain the collected information for so long as it continues to provide the Tapjoy Services.

### 3\. How we Share the Information we Collect

We share the information we collect through our advertising platform in the following ways:

  * Publishers and Advertisers. We may share the information with our Publishers and Advertisers to aid in their understanding of how end users are using Partner Apps and engaging with ads. 
  * Service Providers. We may share your information with a variety of service providers who perform services on our behalf. Some of the service providers we use include providers of analytics, payment processing, product fulfillment, technical infrastructure, data services, engineering and other technical support, and email and customer support. We may share information about you with service providers only to enable them to perform their services. 
  * Tapjoy Affiliates. We may share your information among Tapjoy affiliates (for purposes hereof, the term “affiliate” means an entity controlled by, controlling or under common control with Tapjoy including Tapjoy Korea Co. (Korea), Ltd., 5Rocks, Inc. (Korea), Tapjoy Japan K.K. (Japan), Tapjoy Limited (U.K.), Tapjoy Wireless Applications Technology (Beijing) Ltd. (China), and any future Tapjoy affiliates referred to herein collectively as the “Tapjoy Affiliates”) so that we can better provide advertising that is relevant to you. 
  * Legal Purposes. We may share your information when we believe in good faith that such sharing is reasonably necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities or to comply with legal process to the extent permissible by applicable laws. We may also share your information in situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service; or to respond to the claims of violation of the rights of third parties and/or to protect the rights, property and safety of Tapjoy, our employees, users, or the public and obtaining your consent is difficult. This may involve the sharing of your information with law enforcement, government agencies, courts, and/or other organizations. 
  * Business Transaction. We may share your information in connection with any merger, reorganization, a sale of some or all Tapjoy assets, or a financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company. 
  * Consent. We may share your information in any other circumstances where we have your consent. 
  * Aggregated Data. We may aggregate and/or anonymize information collected through the Ad Platform so that the information can no longer be associated with your specific device. As a result, our use and disclosure of aggregated and/or anonymized information is not restricted by this Privacy Policy, and it may be used and disclosed to others without limitation.

### 4\. Opting Out of Tapjoy Interest-Based Advertising

As described above, we use the information we collect when you use our Partner Apps or visit our website for purposes including in order to serve you with interest-based ads based on your inferred interests, preferences and location.

If you prefer not to receive ads that are tailored to your interests, you can opt out of Tapjoy using your information for this purpose at any time by going to the Tapjoy Opt-Out page: <http://home.tapjoy.com/info/third-party-opt-out/>. You can also usually opt out of the receipt of all in-app interest-based ads by using your device’s privacy settings. Each operating system (e.g., iOS, Android) provides its own instructions on how to prevent the delivery of such in-app ads. You may review the support materials and/or the privacy settings for the respective operating systems in order to opt-out of interest-based in-app ads. Please note that if you opt out of Tapjoy using your information for interest-based advertising you may still receive “generic” ads from us that are not based on your inferred interests.

## Tapjoy Web Services Privacy Practices

1\. The Information We Collect. When you use Tapjoy Web Services, we collect the following types of information from and about you. Please do not use Tapjoy Web Services if you do not agree to the collection and use of your information as detailed below.

Information about you. We collect information from you during your use of the Tapjoy Web Services, which may include your name, username, password, email address, postal address, phone number, and payment information. If you use Tapjoy to create an Advertiser or Publisher account, we may also require you to provide financial information such as your tax ID, VAT, or sales tax registration number or any other relevant tax number and credit card information. We collect information from you that you provide or post on the Tapjoy Web Services or allow us to access when you do certain things, such as when you: 

  * Register to use the Tapjoy Web Services
  * Edit your profile
  * Contact us for customer support
  * Respond to a survey or register for a promotion
  * Participate in sweepstakes or contents
  * Request certain features (e.g., newsletters, updates, or other products)
  * Connect with the Tapjoy Web Services or otherwise allow us to access certain information about you via a social media service
  * Submit feedback to us.

If you choose to voluntarily provide it, we may also collect certain demographic information about you, such as your gender and the apps you use the most. We may also collect user-generated content you post to the Tapjoy Web Services, such as in a discussion board, blog, or other forum. You understand that we cannot control what other users do with any content (including without limitation images, ratings, captions, and comments) you voluntarily disclose for such users to view. If you have allowed other users to have access to your content, those other users may make your content publicly available to be collected and used by others, or to be redistributed through the Internet and other media channels. 

Information from you about others. If you choose to use our referral service to invite a friend to use Tapjoy, we will ask you for your friend’s email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit Tapjoy. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

We also provide registered Publishers or Advertisers with the option of adding users to their accounts. When they do so we will collect the email address of the individual they wish to add. We will then send that individual a one-time email informing them they have been added. 

Information from Third Parties. We may collect, process and store your user ID associated with any social media account (such as your Facebook account) that you use to sign in to or otherwise connect with the Tapjoy Web Services. When you sign in to your account with your social media account information, or otherwise connect your social media account with the Tapjoy Web Services, you consent to our collection, storage, and use, in accordance with this Privacy Policy, of the information that you choose to make available to us through the social media interface. This could include, without limitation, any information that you have made public in connection with your social media account, information that the social media service shares with us, or information that is disclosed as being shared during the sign-in process. Please see your social media provider’s privacy policy and help center for more information about how they share information when you choose to connect your account. 

Anonymous or De-Identified Data. We may anonymize and/or de-identify information collected through the Tapjoy Web Services so that the information no longer relates to you. As a result, our use and disclosure of aggregated and/or de-identified information is not restricted by this Privacy Policy, and it may be used and disclosed to others without limitation.

Automatically Collected Information. When you use the Tapjoy Web Services, there is certain information that we may collect automatically about your computer or device as detailed immediately below. Please note that we may combine the information we collect automatically with the information we collect from and about you.

Device/Usage Information. When you interact with the Tapjoy Web Services, we may automatically collect information such as (a) IP addresses, unique device identifiers (e.g. Android ID, ID for Advertising (IDFA), ID for Vendors (IDFV), MAC address, or other device IDs), and other information about your device(s) browser types, browser language, operating system, the state or country from which you accessed the services; and (b) information related to the ways in which you interact with the Tapjoy Web Services, such as: referring and exit pages and URLs, platform type, the number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time you used the services, error logs, and other similar information. As described further below, we may use third party analytics providers and technologies, including cookies and similar tools, to assist us in understanding how the Tapjoy Web Services are used. 

Location Information. We may make offers available to you that ask you for, access, or track geo-location-based information from your mobile device while downloading or using our mobile app or accessing our websites through a mobile device. If we make these offers available to you, and you consent to enable such services, we will receive information about the country, state and/or city in which you are located to provide you with the requested services including geographically relevant features, offers, applications, and application recommendations. 

Cookies and other technologies. When you use the Tapjoy Web Services, we use persistent and session cookies and other similar technologies to perform various tasks including to: (a) store your username and password; (b) analyze the usage; (c) customize the Tapjoy Web Services to your preferences; and (d) display advertising. You can find more information about cookies and how to manage them at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser settings to decline cookies by visiting your browser’s help page. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some features of the Tapjoy Web Services. By using the Tapjoy Web Services with your browser set to accept cookies you are consenting to our use of cookies in the manner described above. 

In addition to cookies, we and/or our third party advertising partners may use a technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs) that help us better manage and analyze content. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may also include Web beacons in e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether the message has been opened and for other analytics purposes.

2\. Online Analytics and Tailored Advertising  
Online Analytics. To help us better understand your use of the Tapjoy Web Services, we may use third-party web analytics providers, such as Google Analytics. These service providers use the sort of technology described in the “Automatically-Collected Information” Section above. The information collected by this technology will be disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers, who use the information to evaluate users’ use of the websites. To prevent Google Analytics from collecting or using your information, you may install the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

Tailored Advertising. Third parties whose products or services are accessible or advertised via the Tapjoy Web Services may also use cookies or similar technologies to collect information to help them (i) inform, optimize, and serve ads based on past visits to the Tapjoy Web Services and other services and (ii) report how our ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to the Tapjoy Web Services. We also allow other third parties (e.g., ad networks and ad servers) to serve interest-based ads to you, and to access their own cookies or similar technologies on your computer or other device you use to access the Tapjoy Web Services. We neither have access to, nor does this Privacy Policy govern, the use of tracking technologies that may be placed by non-affiliates, third party ad technologies, or any other non-affiliated third parties. Those parties may permit you to opt out of ad targeting as described below. You may receive interest-based advertising on your computer through a web browser. If you are interested in more information about interest-based browser advertising and how you can generally control cookies from being put on your computer to deliver such advertising (i.e., not just for the Tapjoy Web Services), you may visit the [Network Advertising Initiative’s Consumer Opt-Out Link](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s Consumer Opt-Out Link](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or [Truste’s Advertising Choices Page](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note that to the extent advertising technology is integrated into the Tapjoy Web Services, you may still receive ads even if you opt-out of interest-based advertising. In that case, the ads will just not be tailored to your interests. Also, we do not control any of the above opt-out links and are not responsible for any choices you make using these mechanisms or the continued availability or accuracy of these mechanisms. 

When using the MyTapjoy mobile app and/or other Tapjoy mobile apps you may also receive interest-based in-app ads. Each operating system (e.g., iOS, Android) provides its own instructions on how to prevent the delivery of such in-application ads. You may review the support materials and/or the privacy settings for the respective operating systems in order to opt-out of interest-based in-app ads. For any other devices and/or operating systems, please visit the privacy settings for the applicable device or operating system or contact the applicable platform operator. 

3\. How we Use Your Information.  
We use the information we collect from and about you through the Tapjoy Web Services to:

  * Provide the services
  * Manage your account
  * Communicate with you, including responding to your inquiries, informing you about products and services in accordance with your marketing preferences, and notifying you of new features
  * Fulfill your requests for products and services and conduct business with you (e.g. reporting and payment)
  * Generate and review reports about our user base and service usage patterns, analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, and popularity of the service
  * Improve our content and features and personalize content and advertising you see
  * Tapjoy shall retain the collected information for so long as it continues to provide the Tapjoy Services.

### 4\. How do We Share Your Information?

We will share the information we collect through the Tapjoy Web Services only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties for their own marketing purposes. We may share your information in the following ways:

  * Service Providers. We may share your information with a variety of service providers who perform services on our behalf. These service providers include analytics providers, advertisers, payment processors, product fulfillment providers, providers of technical infrastructure, engineers or other technical support, email providers, and customer support vendors. Unless we tell you otherwise, service providers are required to only use your information on our behalf and cannot use it for their own purposes. 
  * Tapjoy Affiliates. We may share your information among Tapjoy Affiliates so that we can better provide advertising that is relevant to you. 
  * Social Networks. If you interact with social media features on our services, such as the Facebook Like button, or use your social media credentials to comment on our blog or log-in, these features may collect information about your use of the Tapjoy Web Services, as well as post information about your activities to your profile page on the social media service. Your interactions with social media companies are governed by their privacy policies. 
  * Legal Purposes. We may share your information when we believe in good faith that such sharing is reasonably necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities or to comply with legal process to the extent permissible by applicable laws. We may also share your information in situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service; or to respond to the claims of violation of the rights of third parties and/or to protect the rights, property and safety of Tapjoy, our employees, users, or the public and obtaining your consent is difficult. This may involve the sharing of your information with law enforcement, government agencies, courts, and/or other organizations. 
  * Business Transaction. We may share your information in connection with any merger, reorganization, a sale of some or all Tapjoy assets, or a financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company. 
  * Consent. We may share your information in any other circumstances where we have your consent. 

### 5\. Accessing and Deleting Your Information.

Through your account settings, you may access and, in some cases, change or delete your username and password, email address, and user profile information that you have previously entered. The information you can view and update through your account settings may change as the Tapjoy Web Services change. You may also request to access or remove personal information we have about you by emailing us at [privacy@tapjoy.com](mailto:privacy@tapjoy.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case, we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### 6\. Your Choices

You have a number of choices as you use the Tapjoy Web Services:

  * Commercial Marketing. If you do not want to receive email or other commercial communications from us, please indicate your preference in your profile, by emailing us at privacy@tapjoy.com, or by following the unsubscribe options contained in commercial messages you receive from us. Please note that it may take some time for us to process your request, consistent with applicable law.
  * Publisher and Advertiser Accounts. If your name has been added to a Publisher or Advertiser account and you wish to no longer have your email address used you may contact us at [privacy@tapjoy.com](mailto:privacy@tapjoy.com)
  * Account Deletion. You may request deletion of your account by sending an e-mail to privacy@tapjoy.com. Please note that some information may remain in our private records after deletion of your account. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your personal information after you delete your account, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.

## Tapjoy Privacy Practices for Both the Ad Platform and Web Services

1\. How we Secure Your Information

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access to your information and to maintain data security. These safeguards take into account the sensitivity of the information that we collect, process and store and the current state of technology. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, the Internet and the services are not 100% secure so we cannot assure you that information we collect or store will be protected from all unauthorized access and thereby used in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. 

2\. International Users

If you are located outside the United States and choose to use our services, engage with ads served by Tapjoy, and/or provide information to us, that information is provided to Tapjoy in the United States, and may be and processed and stored in the United States and otherwise outside of your country of residence, by Tapjoy and by third parties with whom we share in accordance with this Privacy Policy. By using the services, you consent to the collection, transfer, use, storage and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy, including to the export of your information outside of your country of residence. 

3\. Children

Tapjoy does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly allow such persons to use our services. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for Tapjoy or send any information about yourself to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verified parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@tapjoy.com](mailto:privacy@tapjoy.com). 

4\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in the law, our data collection and use practices, the features of our services, or advances in technology. Please check this page periodically for changes. Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the changes here and may notify you by email or other means prior to the change becoming effective. Please review the changes carefully. Your continued use of our services following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you consent to and accept those changes. 

5\. Links to Third Party Sites and Services

Our services may contain links to third-party websites, including social media services. Your use of these features may result in the collection, processing or sharing of information about you, depending on the feature. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites or services that may be linked on our services. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites or services. The information you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by our Privacy Policy. We strongly encourage you to read such third parties’ privacy policies.

6\. Do Not Track Requests 

Many browsers and devices allow the user to limit tracking by enabling a preference called “Do Not Track.” Tapjoy recognizes such preferences, and responds to them when they are enabled in a device or browser by providing generic advertising offers only, rather than using collected data to provide targeted advertising offers.

7\. Notice to California Users

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties. As explained above, Tapjoy does not sell or share your personal information with third parties for their own marketing purposes.

8\. Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please send us a message to [privacy@tapjoy.com](mailto:privacy@tapjoy.com), mail us at Tapjoy, Inc., 111 Sutter Street, 12th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94104, Attn: Privacy, or call us at 415-766-6900. 

Tapjoy Privacy Policy updated Feb. 27, 2015.
